Shuja Akbar | Backend Developer

Phone#+923005376182 Email: shujaakbar2020@gmail.com Portfolio: https://shujaakbar.com

Professional Profile

Backend developer and backend solution architect with TWO years of experience. Developed and Deployed large scale micro-services applications with hybrid architecture. Seeking for opportunity to work within hybrid environment to exhibit and endorse my skills.

Skill Highlights

- Microservices Development
- RESTfull APIs
- Infrastructure Management(AWS)
- Linux Adminstration
- Load Balancing(NGINX)
- Databases(PostgreSQL)

Programming Languages

Python(Flask, Django, Selenium)

DevOps Tools

- Kubernetes
- Git(Github Actions, Git Flow)
- Docker
- SSH

Experience

Jul 2021 - Present

Edraak Systems Backend Developer

- Design and Develop the complete Backend architecture with **Diango**
 - Dockerize the complete infrastructure
 - Deploy it on custom configured local Servers for staging and testing phase
 - Migrate and Ship local Docker Containers to AWS EC2 instances and AWS ECR

Sep 2020 - Feb 2021 Blush and Blooms Full Stack Developer

 Work as Freelance and also Team Lead for developing and maintaining Amazon to Woocommerce product extractor APIs.

Aug 2020 - Nov 2019 Get Push Monkey DevOps Internee

Education

➤ Bachelor of Science: Computer Science - 2019 University of Bradford, UK
Refrence will be furnished on demand